Guide to the Anthony Taussig collection of English legal manuscripts
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Taussig Catalog # 148: 19th cent. (24 Mar. 1813) MS opinion of Charles Butler, 1 p. [92.4.21(b) Quaritch] (Box 20)
- Taussig Catalog # 149: 18th cent. (27 Feb. 1796) MS case with opinion of T. Bradshaw, 1 p. [92.4.21(c) Quaritch] (Box 20)
- Taussig Catalog # 150: 18th cent. (9 July 1777) MS case with opinion of John Dunning, 1 p. [92.4.21(d) Quaritch] (Box 20)
- Taussig Catalog # 151: 19th cent. (13 Oct. 1817) MS case with opinion of Edward Sugden, 1 p. [92.4.21(e) Quaritch] (Box 20)
- Taussig Catalog # 152: 1824 (4 June) and 1827 (31 Oct.) two ALS from Sir John Copley to W. Firth, 2 + 1 pp. (Misc76) [92.4.21(f) Quaritch] (Box 20)
- Taussig Catalog # 153: 1741 (25 June) ALS from Sir John Willes to Mr Underwood, 1 p. (Misc. 22) [92.4.21(g) Quaritch] (Box 20)
- Taussig Catalog # 154: 1820-4 three ALS from Lord Redesdale to Francis Cohen (Palgrave), (Misc. 71) [92.4.21(h) Quaritch] (Box 20)
- Taussig Catalog # 155: 17th cent. (1645) MS notice of committee hearing signed by J. Wilde, 1 p. [92.4.21(j) Quaritch] (Box 20)
- Taussig Catalog # 156: 1648 (17 Nov.) ALS from Hugh Wyndham to earl of Leiceste, 1 p. (Misc. 7) [92.4.21 (k) Quaritch] (Box 23)
- Taussig Catalog # 157: 1596 (18 Dec.) MS letter to sheriff of Kent signed by W. Lambarde and another (Misc. 2) [92.2.15 Burmester] (Box 23)
- Taussig Catalog # 158: 16th cent. MS law readings on statutes, 237 ff. [92.4.23 Maggs] (Box 23)
- Taussig Catalog # 159: 1696 (2 Mar., 1 Apr.) two ALS from Christopher Pemberton to sheriff of Cambs and a copy letter from sheriff, 1 + 1 + 1 p. (Misc. 41) [92.5.5 Bristow] (Box 23)
- Taussig Catalog # 160: 17th cent. (c. 1625/30) MS commonplace taken from MS reports c. 1580-1625, 74 ff. [92.5.13 Laywood] (Box 23)
- Taussig Catalog # 161: 19th cent (1812) MS collection on manorial court-keeping - xii +52p [92.6.19(a) Brewer]
- Taussig Catalog # 162: 1754 (25 May and 27 Sep.) two MS letters to Lord Elibank signed by Baron de Montesquieu, 2 + 3 pp. (Misc. 25) [92.6.19(b) Rankin] (Box 23)
- Taussig Catalog # 163: 19th cent. group of ALS to John Gurney, three from Lord Erskine (1811-19) (Misc. 55), three from Edward Law (1812-16) (Misc. 56) and one from Lord Brougham (1831) (Misc. 85); also ALS from Gurney to Lord Tenterden (Misc. 80) [92.11.23(a-c) Bristow], 4 (Box 23)
- Taussig Catalog # 164: 1845 (2 July) ALS from Lord Lyndhurst to Russell Gurney (Misc. 97) [92.11.23(d) Bristow] (Box 23)
- Taussig Catalog # 165: Watkins C., Principles of Conveyancing 1804 (printed), interleaved and annotated with fair copy of Preston's Observations [93.9.11 Bernstein] (Box 23)
- Taussig Catalog # 166: 18th cent. (1728) MS certificate concerning cleaning of Common Pleas rolls, 1 p. [93.10.29 Mayfly] (Box 23)
- Taussig Catalog # 167: 18th cent. (c. 1790) MS copies of cases and opinions of counsel 1738-1790, 69 ff. [93.11.10 Dominic Winter Book Auctions] (Box 23)
- Taussig Catalog # 168: Intrationum excellentissimus liber 1510 (printed), with some additional leaves bound in and annotated [93.11.24 Christie's] (Box 24 (Oversize))
- Taussig Catalog # 169: 17th cent. (1619-24) MS notes of readings on statutes, 375 pp. [93.12.4 Sotheby's] (Box 23)
- Taussig Catalog # 170: 1777 (30 Oct.) ALS from Lord North to Edward Thurlow offering him office of Lord Chief Baron, 6 pp. (Thu1) [94.2.28 John Wilson] (Box 23)
- Taussig Catalog # 171: 1831 (14 May) ALS from Thomas Wilde to Lord Brougham, 3 pp. (Misc. 84) [94.3.23 W. Myers] (Box 23)
- Taussig Catalog # 172: 1831 (14 May) ALS from Thomas Wilde to Lord Brougham, 3 pp. (Misc. 84) [94.3.23 W. Myers] (Box 23)
- Taussig Catalog # 173: 1742 (14 Dec.) ALS from Edward Southwell to Michael Foster (F52) [94.4.11 Slade] (Box 25 (Oversize))
- Taussig Catalog # 174: 19th cent. 19 receipts for fees paid by Treasury to various Attorneys-General [94.6.17 Mayfly] (Box 23)
- Taussig Catalog # 175: 17th cent. (1689-95) British Merlin1688 (printed), interleaved and annotated with detailed notes of income and expenditure of John Chesshyre [94.6.18 Frognal] (Box 23)
- Taussig Catalog # 176: 18th cent. MS collection of copy cases and opinions of counsel 1708-61 and 1778, 456 pp. [94.9.15 Bloomsbury Book Auctions] (Box 26 (Oversize))
- Taussig Catalog # 177: 1814 (18 Apr.) ALS from Henry Bickersteth to his brother, 3 pp. (Misc. 58) [94.10.24 W. Myers] (Box 23)
- Taussig Catalog # 178: 18th cent. MS five copy letters to and by Michael Foster concerning the trial of Samuel Goodere for murder (F40-44) [94.11.9 J. Rees] (Box 23)
- Taussig Catalog # 178.1: 19th cent. (c. 1809) G. Cooper, A treatise of pleading on the equity side of the High Court of Chancery 1809, interleaved and annotated [MS 94.11.20 P. Crowe] (Box 27)
- Taussig Catalog # 179: 19th cent. (1827) document signed by George IV directing judges to hold special sittings, 2 ff. [94.12.1 and 96.10.18(b) Sophie Dupre] (Box 25 (Oversize))
- Taussig Catalog # 180: 19th cent. (?1830) ALS from Lord Eldon, 1 p. (Misc. 70) [94.12.5(b) John Wilson] (Box 27)
- Taussig Catalog # 181: 1895-1907 three ALS from Harry Eve to Rev. Stebbing (Misc. 115) [94.12.5(c) John Wilson] (Box 27)
- Taussig Catalog # 182: 17th cent. (c. 1681-90) MS of (1) John Selden's Table-Talk, printed 1689 and (2) Noy's Projects, 390 pp. [95.3.1 Bonhams] (Box 27)
- Taussig Catalog # 183: 18th-19th cent. MS attorney=s bill book 1786-1789 and 1806-9 -175ff. [95.3.27(a) Bristow] (Box 74)
- Taussig Catalog # 184: 1793 (15 Apr.) ALS from Granville Sharp to John Gurney, 1 p. (Misc. 39) [95.3.27(b) Bristow] (Box 27)
- Taussig Catalog # 185: 18th cent. (c.1731-5) MS precedents iv + 163 pp. [95.4.6 Bloomsbury Book Auctions] (Box 27)
- Taussig Catalog # 186: 1761-3 four ALS from William Blackstone to Lord Shelburne: (1) 4 Aug. 1761 (Bla5); (2) 19 Oct. 1761 (Bla6); (3) 27 Dec. 1761 (Bla7) and (4) 22 July 1762 (Bla8) [95.6.29(a) Christie's] (Box 27)
- Taussig Catalog # 187: 1766 two ALS from William Blackstone to Lord Shelburne: (1) 4 Aug. 1766 (Bla15) and (2) 9 Oct. 1766 (Bla16) [95.6.29(b) Christie's] (Box 27)
- Taussig Catalog # 188: 18th cent. MS poem "A Friendship: An Ode," attributed to William Blackstone, 4 pp. [95.6.29(c) Christie's] (Box 27)
- Taussig Catalog # 189: 1762 (12 Dec.) ALS from William Blackstone to Lord Shelburne (Bla13) [95.9.20 Lionheart Autographs New York ex Christie's 29.6.95] (Box 27)
- Taussig Catalog # 190: 1800 (4 Mar.) ALS from William Garrow to Thomas Erskine, (Misc. 44) [95.11.29(a) W. Myers] (Box 27)
- Taussig Catalog # 191: 19th cent. (c. 1830) ALS from Sir James Alan Park to Thomas Kenyon, 1 p. (Misc. 82) [95.11.29(b) W. Myers] (Box 27)
- Taussig Catalog # 192: 19th cent. (c. 1898) MS autobiography of John Whitehead in three exercise books (79 + 80 + 77 ff.) [96.1.20(a) A.R. Heath], 3 (Box 27)
- Taussig Catalog # 192.1: 18th cent. (1762) MS authority from Charles Yorke to Samuel Grubb to receive his salary, 1 p. [96.1.20(b) A.R. Heath] (Box 27)
- Taussig Catalog # 193: 19th cent. (1852-5) MS pocket-book of a constable, 70 pp. [96.5.7 J. Browning] (Box 27)
- Taussig Catalog # 194.1-194.2: Euer S Doctrina placitandi 1677 (printed), bound in 2 vols., interleaved and annotated in 18th cent. [96.5.21 J. Rees] (Box 27)
- Taussig Catalog # 195: 1789 (22 Nov.) ALS from George III to Lord Thurlow, 1 p. (Thu6) [96.6.26 J. Wilson] (Box 28)
- Taussig Catalog # 196: 1810 (10 Mar.) ALS from Lord Ellenborough to Lord Palmerston, 2 pp. (Misc. 54) [96.7.17(a) Sophie Dupre] (Box 28)
- Taussig Catalog # 198: 1761 (2 Apr.) ALS from William Blackstone to Lord Shelburne, 2 pp. (Bla4) [96.7.22 Lionheart Autographs New York ex Christie's 29.6.95] (Box 28)
- Taussig Catalog # 199: 19th cent. (1836-44) MS Yorkshire attorney's bill book, xxii + 155 ff. [96.7.30 Chaucer Head] (Box 28)
- Taussig Catalog # 200: 20th cent. (1933-8) MS book of barrister's receipts and expenses, 181 pp. [96.8.22 Bristow] (Box 28)
- Taussig Catalog # 201: 19th cent. MS collection of copy cases to and opinions of counsel, 111 ff. [96.9.17 A.R. Heath] (Box 28)
- Taussig Catalog # 202: 17th cent. (c. 1624) MS copy of Cade's petition against abuses in Chancery, 1 p. [96.10.17 R. Rubin] (Box 28)
- Taussig Catalog # 203: 1818 (13 Oct.) ALS from Lord Ellenborough to Lord Sidmouth, 2 pp. (Misc. 66) [96.10.21(b) W. Myers] (Box 28)
- Taussig Catalog # 204: 1727 (Mar. 25) MS copy of letter concerning duty on brandy, 1 p. (Misc. 17) [96.10.21(c) Bristow] (Box 28)
- Taussig Catalog # 205: 19th cent. (c. 1845) ALS from Sir Edward Alderson to Sir John Gurney, 3 pp. (Misc. 96) [96.10.21(d) Bristow] (Box 28)
- Taussig Catalog # 206: 19th cent. Heads of a bill for amending the law of burglary (printed), with MS annotations by Charles Abbott and Lord Eldon, 1 p. [96.11.26 A.R. Heath] (Box 28)
- Taussig Catalog # 207: Statham Abridgment (c. 1490) (printed), with leaves inserted and MS annotations [96.11.28 Christie's Australia] (Box 28)
- Taussig Catalog # 208: 18th cent. (1747) MS calendar of prisoners in Surrey county gaol, 8 pp. [96.12.13 Dominic Winter Book Auctions] (Box 28)
- Taussig Catalog # 209: 18th cent. (early) MS notes of cases in King's Bench c. 1706-9, 91 ff. [96.12.13?, 97.1.21 A.R. Heath] (Box 28)
- Taussig Catalog # 210: 1779 (10 Nov.) ALS from William Blackstone to William Eden, 3 pp. (Bla17) [97.3.13 Phillips] (Box 28)
- Taussig Catalog # 211: 17th cent. MS of Lord Keeper's speech on ship-money 1737, 8 pp. [97.4.23(a) Bloomsbury Book Auctions] (Box 28)
- Taussig Catalog # 212: 18th cent. (1724/5) MS report of committee to inquire into Chancery Masters' accounts, 34 pp. [97.4.23(b) Bloomsbury Book Auctions] (Box 25 (Oversize))
- Taussig Catalog # 213: 1778 (23 Jan.) ALS from Richard Burn, 1 p. (Misc. 34) [97.5.16(a) W. Myers] (Box 28)
- Taussig Catalog # 214: 19th cent. (c. 1800) ALS from Edward Law, 1 p. (Misc. 47) [97.5.16(b) W. Myers] (Box 28)
- Taussig Catalog # 215: 1805 (9 Sep.) ALS from Vicary Gibbs giving legal opinion, 1 p. (Misc. 50) [97.5.16(c) W. Myers] (Box 28)
- Taussig Catalog # 216: 1819 (25 Aug.) ALS from Sir David Cathcart to Sir James Mackinstos, 4 p. (Misc. 69) [97.5.16(d) W. Myers] (Box 28)
- Taussig Catalog # 217: F. Buller, Nisi prius (1775) (printed), interleaved and annotated [97.5.21(a) J. Rees] (Box 28)
- Taussig Catalog # 218.1-218.2: F. Buller, Nisi prius (1775) (printed), bound in 2 vols., interleaved and annotated [97.5.21(b) J. Rees], 2 (Box 29)
- Taussig Catalog # 219: 17th cent. (c. 1638) MS argument of Judge Crooke on ship-money [97.6.5 Bloomsbury Book Auctions] (Box 29)
- Taussig Catalog # 220: 1793 (4 Oct.) AL unsigned re: Bristol Bridge riot, 7 pp. (Misc. 40) [97.6.19 Knowles] (Box 29)
- Taussig Catalog # 221: 20th cent (1901-2) 8 printed assize calendars for Lancester, Liverpool and Manchester annoted in MS. [97.6.22 Clifford Elmer] (Box 29)
- Taussig Catalog # 222: 1741 (27 Feb) ALS from Michael Foster to his brother - 1p. [97.6.26(a) A.R. Heath] (Box 29)
- Taussig Catalog # 223: 19th cent (1808) MS case to and opinion of Charles Abbottt. [97.6.26(b) A.R.Heath] (Box 29)
- Taussig Catalog # 224: 17th cent (?1689) MS copy of petition to House of Commons - 1p [97.6.26(e) A.R. Heath] (Box 29)
- Taussig Catalog # 225: 1717 (15 July) ALS from Hammon L=Estrange - 1p (Misc13) [96.7.27(f) A.R.Heath] (Box 29)
- Taussig Catalog # 226: 1780 (6 Oct) ALS from Lord Conyngham to Joshua Sharp - 2pp (Misc28) [97.6.26(g) A.R. Heath] (Box 29)
- Taussig Catalog # 227: 18th cent MS Customs of manor of Corsham, Wiltshire - 27pp [97.6.30(a) Ephemera dealer]
- Taussig Catalog # 228: 18th cent. (1742) MS document signed by T. Hussey authorising reward for capture of highwayman, 1 sh. [97.6.30(b) Knowles] (Box 29)
- Taussig Catalog # 229: 19th cent. (1836) MSS seven documents relating to poor law dispute between parishes in Staffordshire [97.6.30(c) Knowles] (Box 29)
- Taussig Catalog # 230: 17th cent. (end) MS collection of entries, 160 pp. [97.7.9 A.R. Heath] (Box 29)
- Taussig Catalog # 231: Tomlin's Explanation of Wills (1787) (printed), copies of two cases to and opinions of John Holliday (5 and 9 Jan. 1789), written on endpapers [97.7.30 J. Rees] (Box 29)
- Taussig Catalog # 232: 1627 (14 Nov.) ALS from John Strode to Francis Chaldecot giving legal advice, 1 p. (Misc. 5) [97.11.18(a) Sophie Dupre] (Box 29)
- Taussig Catalog # 233: 1817 (12 Oct.) ALS from Thomas Erskine, 3 pp. (Misc. 64) [97.11.13(b) Sophie Dupre] (Box 29)
- Taussig Catalog # 234: 1818 (18-19 Oct.) MS copies of letters from Prince Regent to Lord Ellenborough and Lord Ellenborough to Prince Regent, 4 pp. (Misc. 67) [97.11.18(c) Sophie Dupre] (Box 29)
- Taussig Catalog # 235: 1809 (7 Aug.) ALS from Vicary Gibbs, 2 pp. (Misc. 53) [97.11.28 J. Wilson] (Box 29)
- Taussig Catalog # 236: 1761-2 four ALS from William Blackstone to Lord Shelburne: (1) 9 Mar. 1761 (Bla11); (2) 11 Mar. 1761 (Bla2); (3) 12 Mar. 1761 (Bla3) and (4) 7 Sep. 1762 (Bla9) [91.1.19(a-d) Lionheart Autographs New York ex Christie's 29.6.1995] (Box 29)
- Taussig Catalog # 237: 1762 two ALS from William Blackstone to Lord Shelburne: (1) 22 Oct. 1762 (Bla11) and (2) 11 Dec. 1762 (Bla12); also ALS from Lord Shelburne to William Blackstone 11 Sep. 1762 (Bla10) [98.1.19(e-g) Lionheart Autographs New York ex Christie's 29.6.1995] (Box 29)
- Taussig Catalog # 238: 18th cent. (3 Sep. 1754) MS case with autograph opinion of Edward Leeds [98.2.16 W. Myers] (Box 29)
- Taussig Catalog # 239: 1813 (26 June) ALS from Francis Hargrave, Jr., 1 p. (Misc. 57) [98.3.2 Sophie Dupre] (Box 29)
- Taussig Catalog # 240: 17th cent. (c. 1680) MS autograph opinion of Francis Pemberton, 1 p. [98.3.23(a) Bristow] (Box 29)
- Taussig Catalog # 241: 17th cent. (1662) MS grant of court leet by James I, s. sh. [98.3.23(b) Bristow] (Box 29)
- Taussig Catalog # 242: 17th cent. MS (1) notes from Coke on Littleton and (2) copies of cases to and opinions of counsel, 40 pp. [98.4.3 A.R. Heath] (Box 29)
- Taussig Catalog # 243: 17th cent. (1655) MS record of examinations on charge of bugger, 8 pp. [98.4.4 A.R. Heath] (Box 29)
- Taussig Catalog # 244: 18th cent. MS precedents with copies of opinions of counsel, 340 pp. [98.4.28 J. Rees] (Box 29)
- Taussig Catalog # 245: 1833 (6 Oct.) ALS from Thomas D'Oyly to Benning & Saunders, 2 pp. (Misc. 88) [98.5.3 J. Browning] (Box 29)
- Taussig Catalog # 246: 19th cent. (1847) MS case to and autograph opinion of T.N. Talfourd, 1 p. [98.5.6 J. Browning] (Box 29)
- Taussig Catalog # 247: 1832 (5 Dec.) ALS from Lord Tenterden to Lord Melbourne re: Marshalsea prison, 3 pp. (Misc. 87) [98.6.1(a) J. Browning] (Box 31)
- Taussig Catalog # 248: 1728 (14 June) ALS from James Reynolds to unnamed judge, 1 p. (Misc. 19) [98.6.1(b) J. Browning] (Box 31)
- Taussig Catalog # 249: 18th cent. (1788) MS minutes of court martial, 29 pp. [98.6.1(c) J. Browning] (Box 31)
- Taussig Catalog # 250: 1682 (20 Nov.) LS from Heneage Finch to Lady Clifford, 1 p. (Misc. 10) [98.6.1(d) J. Browning] (Box 31)
- Taussig Catalog # 251: 19th cent. MS notebook in hand of Edward Hyde East containing notes relating to his Pleas of Crown (printed 1803), 371 pp. [98.6.4 Nineteenth Century Bookshop, USA] (Box 31)
- Taussig Catalog # 251.1: C.Fearne, An essay on the learning of contingent remainders, 2nd ed., 1773 (printed), interleaved and annotated [98.6.11 J. Rees] (Box 31)
- Taussig Catalog # 252: 19th cent. (c. 1802) MS copies of cases to and opinions of counsel, 312 pp. [98.6.12 J. Rees] (Box 31)
- Taussig Catalog # 253: 1866 (16 May) ALS from Sir J. F. Pollock, 4 pp. (Misc. 104) [98.7.8 J. Browning] (Box 31)
- Taussig Catalog # 254: 18th-19th cent. (1792-1814) MS accounts of society for prosecuting offenders [98.7.17 R. Ford] (Box 31)
- Taussig Catalog # 255: 1839 (14 Apr.) ALS from Lord Cottenham to Lord Denman, 2 pp. (Misc. 92) [98.7.30(a) Farrahar and Dupre] (Box 31)
- Taussig Catalog # 256: 1895 (1 Jan.) ALS from Lord Esher to Lord Davey, 1 p. (Misc. 114) [98.7.30(b) Farrahar & Dupre] (Box 31)
- Taussig Catalog # 257: 1875 (2 Nov.), 1883 (7 Oct.), n.y. (2 Aug.) three ALS from Frederic Harrison to W.H. Duignan (Misc. 110) [98.9.25 Browning] (Box 31)
- Taussig Catalog # 258: Attorney's practice epitomized (1789) (printed), bound with three similar practice guides, interleaved and annotated [98.12.3 Bow Windows] (Box 31)
- Taussig Catalog # 259: 1799 (22 May) ALS from Benjamin Flower to E. Foster re: life in Newgate Prison, 8 pp. (Misc. 43) [98.12.3 J. Wilson] (Box 31)
- Taussig Catalog # 260.1: 19th cent. (mostly 1819-21) MSS large collection of Chancery drafts and copies of cases to and opinions of counsel, 11 vols., c. 10,000 pp., vol. 1 [99.1.3 Phillips (Bath)] (Box 31)
- Taussig Catalog # 260.2-260.6: 19th cent. (mostly 1819-21) MSS large collection of Chancery drafts and copies of cases to and opinions of counsel, 11 vols., c. 10,000 pp., vols. 2-6, 5 (Box 32)
- Taussig Catalog # 260.7-260.11: 19th cent. (mostly 1819-21) MSS large collection of Chancery drafts and copies of cases to and opinions of counsel, 11 vols., c. 10,000 pp., vols. 7-11, 5 (Box 33)
- Taussig Catalog # 261: 1761 (10 Nov.) ALS from Henry Bathurst to Chancellor of Exchequer, 3 pp. (Misc. 30) [99.2.5(a) Stride & Co.] (Box 34)
- Taussig Catalog # 262: 17th cent. (1768) MS letter of authority from Sir Thomas Twisden to Exchequer to pay his salary, 1 p. [99.2.5(c) Stride & Co.] (Box 34)
- Taussig Catalog # 263: 17th cent. MSS documents signed by judges appointing attornies to receive their salaries, 4 sh. [99.2.5(d-g) Stride & Co.] (Box 34)
- Taussig Catalog # 264: 1727 (14 Sep.) ALS by R. Ormond to client, 1 p. (Misc. 18) [99.2.5(h) Stride & Co.] (Box 34)
- Taussig Catalog # 265: 1631 (4 June) letter signed by Sir Robert Heath to sheriff of Wiltshire, 1 p. (Misc. 6) [99.2.23(a) Bonhams] (Box 34)
- Taussig Catalog # 266: 1926 (2 Apr.) ALS from Louise Vinogradoff to Professor Holdsworth, 3 pp. (Misc. 120) [99.3.15 J. Rees] (Box 34)
- Taussig Catalog # 267: 18th cent. (1731 and 1793) MSS, two sales leases of chambers in Lincoln's Inn, 2 sh. [99.5.17 J. Rees] (Box 34)
- Taussig Catalog # 268: 1764 (17 Nov.) ALS from William Blackstone re: Oxford University Press, 3 pp. (Bla14) [99.6.2(a) Christie's] (Box 34)
- Taussig Catalog # 269: 1750 (23 Oct.) ALS from Sir John Willes re: Blackstone, 1 p. (Bla18) [99.6.2(b) Christie's] (Box 34)
- Taussig Catalog # 270: Attorneys practice epitomized 1778 (printed), bound with three similar practice manuals, interleaved and annotated [99.6.14 J. Rees] (Box 34)
- Taussig Catalog # 271: 17th cent. MSS, two humorous lists of jurors, 2 pp. [99.6.18 Bristow] (Box 34)
- Taussig Catalog # 272: 19th cent. MS vestry book of Milton Abbot, Dorset 1842-65, c. 192 pp. [99.7.17(a) Aitchison] (Box 34)
- Taussig Catalog # 273: 19th cent. (1839-46) MS lawyer's letterbook, 236 + 13 pp. [99.7.16(b) Aitchison] (Box 34)
- Taussig Catalog # 274: 18th cent. (c. 1792-6) MS Edward Oldfield's book of conveyancing precedents, 267 pp. [99.7.28 Castle Hill Books] (Box 34)
- Taussig Catalog # 275: 17th cent. (1673) MS grant by Charles II to Sir Heneage Finch of control of idiots and lunatics, 2 pp. [99.8.3 Bristow ex Bloomsbury Book Auctions] (Box 34)
- Taussig Catalog # 276: 18th cent. (1736-90) MS workhouse records for parish of Gasper, Somerset, c. 200 pp. [99.8.17 David Lay Auctions] (Box 35 (Oversize))
- Taussig Catalog # 277: 19th cent. MS attorney's notebook, 213 pp. [00/8.24 Burmester] (Box 34)
- Taussig Catalog # 278: Buller, Nisi prius 1793 (printed) interleaved and annotated [99.8.28 Burmester] (Box 34)
- Taussig Catalog # 279: 18th cent. (1743) MS collection of papers re: imprisonment, trial and execution of John Brown alias Stephen Wright [99.9.8 J. Rees] (Box 34)
- Taussig Catalog # 280: 18th cent. MS information of Coleman Jones re: attack by mob on 28 Feb. 1874, 4 + 2 pp. [99.9.15 J. Browning] (Box 34)
- Taussig Catalog # 281: 17th cent. (mid) MS commonplace, loose leaves [99.11.5 Phillips] (Box 36 (Oversize))
- Taussig Catalog # 282: 19th cent. (c. 1800) ALS from John Heath to Thomas Erskine, 1 p. (Misc. 45) [99.11.6 A.R. Heath] (Box 34)
- Taussig Catalog # 283: 18th cent. (1712) MS order signed by Edward Northey staying proceedings, 1 p. [99.11.11 Bloomsbury Book Auctions] (Box 34)
- Taussig Catalog # 284: Simmons, Remarks on the constitution and practice of courts martial 1830 (printed), with 14 appended pages of legal questions and answers [2000.1.11 Robert Frew] (Box 37)
- Taussig Catalog # 285: 19th cent. (1813) MS quietus roll of William Fowle, sheriff of Wiltshire [2000.2.9 Aitchison] (Box 38)
- Taussig Catalog # 286: 19th cent. (1823 and 1826 ) four ALS from J.D. Hume to J.C. Herries re: reform of Customs legislation, 24 + 1 + 32 + 4 pp. (Misc. 75) [2000.2.16 J. Browning] (Box 37)
- Taussig Catalog # 287: 1780 (15 and 17 June) 2 ALS: (1) from Samuel Whitbread to Sir John Skynner and (2) from Skynner to Mr. Watley re: site for a new penitentiary 1 + 1 pp. (Misc. 35) [2000.3.15 Farrahar & Dupre] (Box 37)
- Taussig Catalog # 288: 17th cent. (1660s) MS memorandum re: salaries of Welsh judges, 1 p. [2000.5.11 Bloomsbury Books Auctions] (Box 37)
- Taussig Catalog # 289: 1840 (27 Oct.) ALS from Lord Denman to Lord Brougham, 4 pp. (Misc. 95) [2000.5.11 Bloomsbury Book Auctions] (Box 37)
- Taussig Catalog # 290: 1780 (31 May) MS case with autograph opinion of Edward Law [2000.6.11(a) I. Campbell] (Box 37)
- Taussig Catalog # 291: 1758 (4 Dec.) MS case with autograph opinion of William Wynne, 2 pp. [2000.6.11(b) I. Campbell] (Box 37)
- Taussig Catalog # 292: 1849 (12 July) ALS from Lord Brougham, 3 pp. (Misc. 100) [2000.6.11(f) J. Grant] (Box 37)
- Taussig Catalog # 293: 1829 (11 July) ALS from Wiliam Wilberforce to Thomas Erskine, 3 pp. (Misc. 78) [2000.6.11(g) J. Grant] (Box 37)
- Taussig Catalog # 294: 18th cent. (178-) two MSS: (1) assignment from Charles Chaplin of prisoners in Lincoln gaol and (2) appointment of under-sheriff, 2 sh. [2000.6.19 (a-b) Dominic Winter Book Auctions] (Box 37)
- Taussig Catalog # 295: Grotius, De jure belli ac pacis1632 (printed) with inscription by Grotius dated 10 May 1645 [2000.8.22 Chaucer Head] (Box 37)
- Taussig Catalog # 296: 18th cent. Printed cases in House of Lords or Privy Council with some MS annotations. [2000.8.30 Cellar Stories Bookstore] (Box 30 (Oversize))
- Taussig Catalog # 297: 1831 (24 Jan.) ALS from Jeremy Bentham to his nephew George, 1 p. (Misc. 83) [2000.10.3 M. Silverman] (Box 37)
- Taussig Catalog # 298: 19th cent. (1856) MS rules of Benefit Building Society certified. 3 Jan. 1856, 11 ff. [2000.10.17 Aitchison] (Box 37)
- Taussig Catalog # 299: 1787 (23 Feb.) ALS from Duke of Richmond to Lord Sydney re: death sentence, 4 pp. (Misc. 37) [2000.10.30 J. Browning] (Box 37)
- Taussig Catalog # 300: 18th-20th cent. collection of about 50 letters of judges and lawyers, some typed, most MS (Misc. 24, 29, 60, 61, 90 102, 118, 125) [2000.12.1 Stride & Son], 9 (Box 37)
- Taussig Catalog # 301: 19th cent (1817) MS copy of examination of Omar Hall in Mary Ashford murder case, 4 ff. [2000.12.13 Bonhams] (Box 37)
- Taussig Catalog # 302: Watkins, Principles of conveyancing 1800 (printed), interleaved and annotated with observations of Richard Preston [2000.12.15 A.R. Heath] (Box 37)
- Taussig Catalog # 303.1: John Rees's master copies of his catalogues of antiquarian law books 1979-1992 (printed), annotated [2001.2.1 J. Rees] [1 of 3] (Box 37)
- Taussig Catalog # 303.2-303.4: John Rees's master copies of his catalogues of antiquarian law books 1979-1992 (printed), annotated [2001.2.1 J. Rees] [2 of 3], 3 (Box 37)
- Taussig Catalog # 303.5-303.18: John Rees's master copies of his catalogues of antiquarian law books 1979-1992 (printed), annotated [2001.2.1 J. Rees] [3 of 3], 14 (Box 39)
- Taussig Catalog # 304: 19th cent. (30 May 1840) MS quietus roll of Charles Garrard, sheriff of Hertfordshire, 1 sh. [2001.3.8 Dominic Winter Book Auctions] (Box 39)